so how can one know that you're making
progress in the practice if your
practice is going right going wrong well
that's something related to a spoon
before being self transparent and
authentic if you are self transparent
and by that it's meant if you don't if
you don't lie to yourself as in if you
don't try to turn a blind eye to the
truth and in this case in this case the
truth being you are not free from
suffering everybody started a petition
so that that should be your criteria
which means whatever you're doing in
terms of the practice it should be
freeing you from suffering at least a
degree at least to a degree that you can
then start discerning and then use that
criteria to keep doing that thing more
but the reason why it won't be so easy
it's because people are not self
transparent because that's done for the
for the purpose of protecting oneself
from suffering you don't acknowledge
certain truths you don't admit to
yourself you you hold the view you
defend the stance point all then it's
done so you don't expose yourself to
that a substantial suffering so if you
remove that attitude and then you're not
suffering as a result of practice you
can know that you are on a better way to
free yourself from suffering but if you
don't remove that attitude whatever you
end up doing on the pretext of practice
it's gonna be done as a phone cover up
very often you can also ask yourself
whether you're covering things up by see
you if you get upset by when you
encounter other people's views they're
different than yours if you take the
personal if you feel threatened by them
if you are means you're holding on to
your own even if happen those views
happen to be right that you have find
your home that means you're not right
you're right
it's very different than like expecting
a kind of feeling or perceptual like
light just for the blue line oh you know
that means every day what do I do next
after this day the blue stage yeah
there's nothing like that in the
sitter's I'm sure there's plenty of
contemporary meditation being taught on
those lines and if you're meditating
together blue light or whatever you want
by all means but that's not freedom from
suffering you know no suffering lies
only one thing in their thing is
understanding the nature of things
hence the dama dama means phenomena
that's it means things the Dhamma means
knowledge of those and knowledge not
like a informational sort of collecting
the data and like laying it all out in a
psychological manner not understanding
the nature the nature of the original
nature to manifest what's the
fundamental universal nature
you understand that fully you are free
from suffering you can't suffer because
you can't appropriate it and there is
nothing to do even if you never see any
special lights or have special
experiences yes sir Goethe said himself
he was the foremost after the Buddha
according to the Buddha himself he said
sorry food is the foremost after me and
he said you couldn't even see a mere
Goblin let's not have any other
supernatural experience or or a release
he was all clarity of understanding and
mindfulness in wisdom basically and
that's why he was a second after the
Buddha while others who had you know fly
in the air and glide to glide the Sun in
the moon and see the future lives and
past lives and all there's nothing to do
with the freedom from suffering sure it
can be a side effect of it for some
that's irrelevant
so those are people looking for what
kind of no little thing yeah I can show
everybody well because being people's views are
well because being people's views are
generally they stopped by being fully
embedded in their conceit and
self-centeredness vanity often
sensuality so then you just judge that
the new spiritual find inspiration you
judge with those criteria
you know what's unique what's new what's
what's what's uncommon what's lost in
that sense and also very often what can
be kind of exists quickly and can be so
pleasant that fully overwhelms me it's
just extension of sensual craving
basically directed elsewhere so should
you challenge yourself if you want to
see where you're at in the practice did
you put challenges upon yourself like
ascetic practices absolutely especially
if you have none if your life is not if
your life is quite a comfortable easy no
physical discomfort anything like that
absolutely yeah
you use common sense you don't challenge
yourself to the point of risking your
life while you're still unenlightened
it's over the same with wisely avoid a
wild elephant a mad cow or aging dog but
that doesn't mean you would go and
climbed on top of a pelisson and live
sheltered and hidden for the rest of his
life and I think yeah I think we
addressed it before probably but as as
it is it is the case with most people
today on average certain in Europe in
America whenever rich people are soft
like even even even those who are kind
of not as wealthy has to have to work
they still have relatively comfortable
lives in comparison to how it used to be
back in the day in India so so that's
something you have to factor in the
threshold from which you begin
so one of those things that you could
change yourself with this solitude yeah
you're trying to be the alluring well
that is a that is a challenge and that
is also a necessity that's why people
actually congregate and come together
and live together in Peres put up it
also to this conference because solitude
is far more terrifying than anything
else so it's not optional it's something
you your practice should be going
towards that's whether we would say you
you you develop the the recognition of
pleasure in solitude basically you learn
how to find solitude valuable and
pleasing otherwise it won't be and you
can only learn that through the servant
it's an understanding that's why I see
the benefit search and that's how you
see the dangers when the solitude is
absent that's how I develop a value
factual value of solitude so how can a
person do it well it really depends how
far then a person wants to go if they're
thinking about you know practicing
towards honor aren't you Anagha me yeah
you can't be a layperson I mean
theoretically you can be an undergrad a
person but there was more live like a
linguist or leave like a layperson sure
I live like sure sure sure sure you can
do that but even back in the Buddhist
time there was there was not common
usually people would go for but so today
it's kind of virtually impossible if you
want to go that far you would have to
give up the way over householders life
you just can't I mean you can you don't
necessarily have to go and become a monk
but you have to live like renunciate
like somebody who is practicing
restraint lifts cellular life secluded
from people not just secluded by not
engaging with him but living with them
but actually physically physically
removed from people
is necessary certain certainly for the
periods of time so again so you have to
recognize that if you don't want to
leave the life of a layman that you know
then you have to sort of lower down your
expectations in terms of how much you
can develop is a lot of people yeah yeah
being a being like living alone doesn't
mean you're actually alone there's no
sign of you need you need that physical
distance at least initially to discern
exactly to discern the sign of solitude
to descend for the Sun of your own mind
in a way the framework of others as a
phenomena all that basically John any
any sort of establishing of mind you
need you can't just sit in a hole with
30 other people on a retreat even if
you're all perfectly silent you are with
others there are others in that well it
effects the outlook of your experience
at the time when you're present if you
remove yourself from it can you get to
understand the framework of that
experience then yes you can
theoretically be with others and not be
affected by that on that existential
level but as I said we all start with a
mistake of ignorance with a mistake or
video that is beginningless and real as
such which means you have to reverse to
a degree in order to get to see the
nature of things
and then you can go back to some of it
but you still wouldn't be able to live
as a layman somebody who is understood
it properly freed himself from
sensuality to become an around
so again if you recognize the
limitations that you are not willing to
give up as in you don't want to go and
become a monk and so on then you just
have to like measure what you can do in
that set up and try and tailor your lay
setup so if you have to work five days a
week well the other two days I don't
know rent a cabin in the middle of the
forest and that's where you spend it
don't spend the valuable time that you
can have in solitude just socializing
with others
spend it in seclusion study if you still
need to cry for what you need to do and
so on well is there's different kinds of
solitude there's a physical seclusion
little seclusion so oh yeah sure sure I
need met physical seclusion because the
mental seclusion is that's true but in
order to develop a proper mental
seclusion that can only be done through
physical seclusion and yes like again as
a lazy fall a person is not able to have
a complete physical seclusion well then
you do the best out of what you can what
you can so in a sense if you can't be
physically removed from people will at
least spend your time not engaging with
them if you don't have to engage don't
don't talk to them if you have to talk
well then talk the bare minimum don't go
further that's difficult because that's
the form of engagement it is not talking
to the person sitting on there sure sure
that's familiar all in the effect that
just by being by others with others even
if there is a public agreement between
us that we will not speak it's still
others presence of others the assumption
of the external point of view to
yourself all that is present so you just
you do have to be physically removed
some people know some people less for
periods of time to develop certain
clarity I mean just pick a suit a random
80% chance you will be talking about
value of solitude and forestry mode
dwellings and empty lodgings and go
there and you don't waste your time and
that's like one of the reasons why a
person cannot develop these things is
because a house whole life is crowded in
dusty its Christ's obvious people always
people always
you can practice them so that you must
abandon that type of life if you want to
practice and that again even if you
don't want to go and become a monk
so yeah the lifestyle choices matter you
can like not change any aspect of your
lifestyle and expect to develop practice
you can't I mean the precepts are old
and your lifestyle choice things in
terms of looking after yourself yeah
physical health what's what's going too
far what's not going far enough are we
supposed to eat eat just the bare
minimum just so they can get just right
right right I switch me Cheers
yeah keep on breathing keep on walking
because if you're eating very little
obviously you start to waste away mmm
there is no chance first in that kind of
state going on peanut butter are you
absolutely in the mountainous area oh
yeah like especially for the monks what
if they want to live like forest months
Oh Justin names literally in life are
away from other people seclusion means
effort seclusion means exposure to
elements seclusion means ability to
endure seclusion means toughness
physical toughness discomfort that
doesn't bother you did you find
comfortable yeah again as I said
ultimately if a person manages to
properly develop their mind properly
establish a mine in jhana and similar
establishments they will enjoy the
roughness toughness discomfort even more
but in order to get there the order they
need to be able to take a degree of pain
without their mind just melting away
without the mindfulness fizzling out the
moment that discomfort touches them
which is usually why people are afraid
people and I again speak out of personal
experience as a label
you know you get into the meditation
then immediately oh I must stop anything
basically they will result in fatigue
anything they will tire me it will
compromise my mind when I see sick will
make me sick exactly but cold well
that's the thing health it's the hot
late it's the principle that just did
you sort of open this up with it's the
pretty like windy weather said you can't
stop eating because you will you will
die so what you do that you can blame
food for your sexuality because you
weren't there yet there's certain things
you have to stop doing such as sexual
intercourse killing others and so on
that cannot be done also late but things
that are necessary or things that are
helpful can be determined helpful
whether they are rooted in wholesome
intentions so if you if you're mindful if you
so if you if you're mindful if you
develop discernment and if you if you
invest effort in in clarity of your
motivation in regard to the reasons why
you're eating food as the Buddhist
himself said sometimes he would eat two
bowls of food filled to the brim while
he has disciples who live only on a
handful of rice every third day or
whatever but that doesn't mean the
Buddha was sensual it just means that at
that time there was a need for more
either way even if he had temples of
food for no point in that duration of
that action of eating would have he been
rooted in sensuality or in vanity or
desire for physical beauty so heap so he
can be healthy and admired by others no
he ate because he was hungry
that's it but that takes that takes
proper mindfulness because if you are
careless then you're automatically
eating out of sensuality it's same with
health people get obsessed with the
health and we're there
whatever tablet cents and multivitamins
and acupuncture is and all of that that
can help when there is a need for that
help but more often than not people
start protecting it just for the sake of
it but health is very much like the
immune system you'll develop it if you
challenge it if you don't you lose it so
it's not accidental when you here I go
the old monk in Thailand ninety
something years walking pinned about
every single day of his life like for
five kilometres
and live to the old age fully inactive
yeah cuz he built he built basically his
body adjusted yeah exactly through the
exposure through through fatigue effort
strength endurance all of that now if
your life doesn't require that you don't
have to do it specifically although it
will probably be useful to have some
sort of physical discipline something
they will tire you something that will
make you making fun make your heart race
basically so I don't mean like do
spiritual sort of energy flows with your
Tai Chi or some yoga twists and whatnot
you won't actually to tire yourself to
be able to see how can you be mindful
whether you're tired or not
how can you mindfulness remain
unaffected by that because if your
mindfulness and again I'm speaking at
our personal experience Italy but like I
was afraid to get tired I stopped doing
sports stopped exercising because it
would disturb my mindfulness which is
because I didn't know what mindfulness
was so that which I thought was
mindfulness was indeed disturbed by
fatigue by tiredness so I must stop that
but there was a complete mistake I wish
somebody told me sooner
but fortunately like I didn't end up
hurting myself in terms of physically as
many monks do when you stop everything
you just sit for the whole day you don't
do anything and then suddenly you forget
how fit you are you go for a massive
long to dunk or something and you
dislocate you know disc slips and
whatnot and that happens when when body
is just weak you you lost the certain
degree of resilience and strength and
you move up you move a pot plant and
that's it you you end up in a
chiropractor how many times that
happened to people like and all because
just because of the kind of same
attitude if I must not get tired don't
disturb my mindfulness and then becomes
a habit of not getting tired so that's
what I mean you want something that will
tire so that you can see them because if
your mindfulness is disturbed by the
mayor fatigue what are you gonna do when
you're facing death illness dying of
cancer body's shutting down hurting from every
body's shutting down hurting from every
angle no way to rest from it there's no
way and again think how the monks lived
back in the Buddhist day
the edges of Himalayas like tracking for
four months a tent just to meet the
Buddha in time yeah try like today if
you want to do that you need like
military training
I take an average guy all you need to be
doing that the gradual increasing for
like decades to be able to do it so you
want to recognize this necessity and
also indifference toward mindfulness
whether you're fatigued or not because
if your problem mindful it doesn't
matter and then you won't matter whether
you're in a deathbed struggling to breed
or you're perfectly healthy in full
strength and full whatever it doesn't
matter could you discern where the mindfulness
could you discern where the mindfulness
is but yeah if you blame your fatigue if
you bring things you have to do if you
blame work if you blame exercise well
good luck with that like you can sort of
survive like that if you live in a
precious environment that's usually
based on luxury and comfort even if you
don't necessarily recognize it as such
but in the unit's Abbasid a suit today
is a whole the Buddha said is a whole
domain of our service to be abandoned
simply by enduring enduring heat called
discomfort tired hunger enduring insects
enduring elements basically so if you're
not able to endure it if your mind falls
away from it just as a prospect of
enduring you're nowhere near it so
doesn't mean of course the people who
live for the clay people who live in the
cities oh I must go run and live in the
mountain it's not gonna work but you do
need some sort of physical discipline
something they will challenge you and
tire you and make you tougher and
stronger too complicated no of course
not no absolutely not
because again you want to have it rooted
in those reasons because sure yeah
people can be doing exercise for all
sorts of reasons for vanity for wanting
to be the best the quickest is the
strongest Testim that's the number one
reason yeah sure sure sure
yeah well that's that's why often people
will project don't think like you can't
do it for any other reason except the
vanity and then oh then they're also
equally mistakenly project thinking in
order then to do something they won't be
in vanity it must be something
completely different and then they get
doing like Tai Chi or things like that
which again
it's a valid form of exiting for some
but it's not the one you're looking
after you're not gonna make it tougher
or more resilient so you want to look at
things that actually are most economical
with the least effort you get most
result in terms of your exercise so you
don't have to spend five hours training
and running and whatnot well you do the
minimum as a form of discipline as a
form of chore and then it will pertain
to everything else in a positive manner
I suppose a lots of that the type of
work that people used to do generally
there's more physical farm work and so
on sure and that's what done how do you
know no there's none other necessity as
a side effect of that necessity was they
were they were fit and tough and able to
endure but but now you have like gyms in
the cities sure which is basically set
up a luxury but it's all about mirrors
and vanity yeah yeah I was just thinking
that well that's the thing if like it's
not denying the lifestyle has changed so
you can't just go and start plowing the
land and whatever because there is
absolutely no need for that anymore but
you recognize this like certain loss
with that which is that like physical
toughness unable to endure discomfort
and pain so if you want to compensate
for that you don't have to change your
lifestyle to a great degree but exactly
you find you do the training you do the
exercises they will add up to that which
you don't have and especially as a as a
monk who is interested to live like a
forest monk who is interested to live
solely on Pinder but in the remote
dwellings frequenting the forests and
stuff if you just I mean we had that
tear happens like when people were like
15 years younger than us came and stayed
here for a couple of days by the third
day they were dead they were broken just
having to walk five kilometres for their
food it's like done every day and no problem
it's like done every day and no problem
I almost look forward for it so if you
just even even the old ladies who live
nearby my goodness yeah yeah
keep peeking ladies yeah exactly the
teepee seventy-year-old
just hell steep like this I don't know
probably 15 kilos of wolf of tea leaves
in the bag on her back and he's there
like like a Mountain deer just not a
slip nothing she's been doing it her
whole life out of anything
exactly well no that's the thing someone
who hasn't been doing it yeah in order
to know somebody hasn't been doing it in
order to do it more like more often than
not it's like vanity is the reason and
in a way that's fine if that's what
makes you do it but then you just change
the reason and keep doing it so for
somebody who lives in the city if you
want to go and start I don't know
endurance training or strength training
go to a gym that doesn't have the
mirrors that's the first thing it's
absolutely no reason for lifting in
front of a mirror except vanity even
actually even in terms of the form and
developing the proper lifting form for
example in strength training you should
not look in the mirror like the Russian
Olympic team I don't maybe they still do
it but back in the day they used to lift
this complex like running big snatches
in power cleans and so on blindfolded
because you want to learn the Moto X you
want to learn the movement
hence the compound exercises no mirror
strength endurance repetition and
increase in the weight if you want to
look if you want to develop a muscle
bulging out so that you'd be attracting
you cannot do that for wholesome reasons
exactly exactly
so if if you being fit is a result of
your discipline and basically pursuit of
physical toughness and endurance that's
absolutely fine in the same sense as you
being healthy as a result of eating
that's fine just don't because you can't
slip into unwholesome accidentally you
can't accidentally like start eating for
pleasure no you do it by deciding to go
for pleasure you can't accidentally go
and start training with weights and
accidentally do bodybuilding no
bodybuilding is all about basically from
developing proportions developing size
which means it's all about the way you
look which means it's all about the
vanity but then if you don't do any form
of that if you actually
if you actually do the the strength
endurance training then you wouldn't
need more than what like half an hour
three times a week using some proper
strength like put the teens proven been
around for like forty years and and you
wouldn't have to spend like six hours
jogging and running and everything else
notice that you'll be healthy you'll
also be able to take the pain
you wouldn't shy away from discomfort
you wouldn't shy away from physical
fatigue and nor would you would your
mental composure be affected by it could
you train yourself sure or just take a
backpack go in the mountains and walk
live in a tent and you'll get used to it
and you get tougher you get stronger
that's again back in the day but back in
the day like there's no it's not it's
not an accidental that the Buddha kept
referring to like you know leave me like
trying to inspire monks with like
similes of warriors and soldiers and
toughness because it was like that
imagine just like carrying a backpack of
five kilos let alone 15 or 20 kilos and
then hiked for 20 kilometers an uneven
terrain that's a military training day
today that's considered almost like what
a military elite infantry yet that was
your lifestyle and you and you don't
even get to sleep in a nice place you
get to sleep in a route under the root
of a tree so that's what I mean like
people may not think they live a
luxurious life but in comparison it's
very like even here in the hill where we
where we do walk in the bird every
single day five to six kilometres up and
down the mountain rain wind doesn't
matter hmm
overall it's actually quite comfortable
up here and it's quite easy cuz if you
do want to have the ultimate perspective
in your mind how did the the roots of a
tree dweller live you think when they
walked across the entire Bihar to me the
Buddha they were just flying in the air
no they're walking carrying carrying the
bowl which were probably heavy cast-iron
ball and and you think a weak person can
do that
Ketel spots and premise thick felt does
the spell blankets these to use in india
for any stuff it's like fifteen twenty
kilo of weight on you son he lifts sorry
life is yeah they did not have what was
the name of that Baba
make Baba ten thousand pounds eight
eight hundred gram tent or something no
no yeah massive wool blankets canvases
balls in so just just picture that and
picture that doing you do doing that
every day and I don't double that
that's your practice as in that's how
you also practice so that's what I mean
people a bit too precious in a sense
including myself where I started you
think I must all this nothing must
challenge me because that because this
is yeah you stop like that but you had
to see what that that's not where the
problem is the problem is not in your
exercise the problem is not in your
eating taking medicine paying attention
to your health the problem is you doing
those things for wrong reasons which
means it's your reasons that make it a
problem or not so in the same sense as I
was just saying if you want to go and
develop solitude you have to be able to
take it if and they will often require
yet the degree of physical discomfort
independence independence yeah exactly
you won't have like twenty servants
twenty junior among servants around you
just just attending to your every wish
no you won't so it should you have to do
it yourself
which means you have to be able to do it
yourself and you won't be able if your
body is simply not strong enough okay
you come you come to it you just can't
take it can get out of bed out there
after one day's work so that's what I
mean in that sense exercise can start
approximating that for those who don't
work like that
who don't have that net like toughness
developed through work and so on I could
call here
ya can't get your heart pumping whether
through lifting weights or whether
through running if you can even
treadmills and so on but as I said don't
get obsessed about it either like do a
research see which one is the most
economical by that I mean the least you
can do the most you get from it and yeah
I think there's a universal consensus
all those who know of those who don't
identify weights with bodybuilding who
know the difference of like professional
athletes it's like you know heavy
barbell training kettlebells bodyweight
pull-ups and things like that things
they will you know increase your bone
densities joint strength stability all
of that you can do your Tai Chi if you
want in the spare time but you actually
want to stress the body in a controlled
manner that's how I gets tougher
stronger that's how you can eat one meal
a day and going from the mountain and
carry 20 kilos backpack and sleep on a
rock like a baby
and you know you know the difference
even you know out of like our own
experience we knew when you you live in
Europe or some well sort of
well-developed temple and then you know
you like even going to Thailand
and staying in some more rural temples
coming to sri lanka oh it's just that
yeah people who were not prepared
physically well they didn't last long
but those who did had to go through a
lot of pain very quickly because they
just hadn't ready for it
and above all people end up feeling it
feeling the prospect of physical
discomfort challenge endurance fatigue
even even without actually engaging in
it and again it's something we see many
times especially in the monasteries they
were about work lots of work and board
projects and people are to work you just
see the genuine genuine terror in their
eyes because they just gonna be
overwhelmed the mindfully is gonna go
and the thing about sensuality and then
the maddest row like that should worry
you not the fact that you might have to
work or get tired to our exercise the
fact that doing that will push you all
the way back into sensuality that's the
problem there so you can avoid it
initially until you start developing
yourself but if you never make the
effort develop yourself in the right
manner you can avoid it forever because
as I said once your health start to fail
strength is relative for an old person
body failing what used to be weakness it
is now strength in comparison so
lifestyle choices matter don't think you
have for granted don't think your
strengths for granted don't think your
freedom from illness for granted but
actually start emulating and preparing
yourself for when those things go where
were those things start challenging you
physically which wasn't challenging
mentally if you can take it then you can
take your mind even further above it and
really not be affected but as the Buddha
said again in tsubasa suta
there's a whole set of things whole set
of aussolas to be abandoned purely by
enduring by cuffing him out
and that's that's something that's often
missing today people have way too
spiritual so to speak even that exercise
becomes spiritual it doesn't actually
pertain to the physical aspect anymore
certainly lifestyles become too
spiritual no manual labor nothing so if
you pay attention to the if you're
interested in practice you pay attention
to the lifestyle choices choices you
make not just for today and tomorrow but
in the long run as well in fact that in
if you're interested in practice and
developing the environment it was the
body of solitude and so on pay attention
to preparing your body physically to be
able to do it it's easy to keep the
vanity out if you're careful avoid
looking yourself in the mirror to the
compound lifts or general type of
exercises they will stress your body not
necessary resulting in some developing
of proportions and whatnot but you do
need to start stressing yourself and
also in the same manner you can't expect
to just jump into solitude from a busy
life I mean you can you can be forced
into it you can allow yourself to be
forced into it which is usually others
popular going to retreat work and that's
why you get all these little energy
releases and whatnot but it's because of
your lifestyle beforehand but if you
don't go for that you want to start
exposing yourself to that type of stress
gradually but pretty much steadily it's
not optional basically so you recognize
what the goal is which is to be able to
find joy happiness and to prefer the
actual physical solitude and absence of
other people and then to develop
yourself for that physically and
mentally to have mentally stressed
well bye-bye X by Bingle Oh
deciding to be alone for not engaging
any distraction not answer any phone
calls don't go to see anyone for a
period of time there's no distraction no
distraction of course yeah or as I said
if if you are relatively fit physically
can take some pain and toughness yeah
take a backpacking go for like three or
four day hike in a little tent okay
we'll give you a sense of how used to be
and practice in the environment don't
just endure and put up with elements but
actually take your mind above it just
having it a minor headache
little head instance sure thank you
instant relief seeked immediately so if
you just don't take it thank you oh yeah
no so you recognize what how you want to
live and take responsibility for it and
that's how you can take medicine when
you are ill for sake of staying healthy
not out of fear for getting sick that's
how you will eat for the sake of staying
alive and healthy not for beautification
or fear of death no took responsibility
for it that's how you'll exercise in
order to be able to take the pain even
more without being afraid of it
you just a deal with the simple grunting
you know yeah taking away from the
elements but not overly protective
protecting you from there is it things
that why do you need the thick soft
mattress why is that
cuz the body's not used to sleep on
heart why is it not used to cuz you
never expose it
you never stressed it in a manner and
it's not it's not empty ascetic
practices whether it's empty or not it's
whether you don't do it for the right
reasons or not I mean the utmost most
inspiring ascetic performance can be
more empty than eating and exercising if
you do it for the wrong reasons because
if you do eating and exercising for the
right reasons the reason that you
understand the reason they will pertain
to your freedom from suffering through
your effort yeah that's what makes it
awesome but if you're just going self
mortifying yourself foot for just the
reason of whatever proving to yourself
that you do it crushing us or whatever
without any grain of reflection or
inside yeah in that sense it's
completely wrong being skinny burns
means I'm on the right path
yeah exactly yeah it doesn't I mean they
whatever that suit is as well the King I
don't if his personality or the other
one anyway we went to visit the Buddha
you stay in the scooty on the way I
could he was walking through the park
but all this young and healthy monks
were doing walking meditation like
pacing from one tree to the other back
and forth and they were quite happy and
he said wow look at that
this teaching is so wonderful well he
praised the Buddha the Buddha said once
you see praiseworthy me I said well like
for example just now this teaching is so
wonderful when you have like men in
their youth still fully able to access
sensual pleasures in your life K Roth
and they're happy about it they're very
content while you go to the other
settings in Brahmins they're all dried
up skin and bone just hating on everyone
I'm happy so you have to stop discerning
the reasons behind directions whether
that's those actions are aimed at health
life strength lifestyle in general you
are responsible for making a wholesome
or unwholesome they're not necessarily
determined by themselves very few are
known celibacy of course that's always a
wholesome killing harming lying stealing
that's always unwholesome but pretty
much everything else it's going to be
unwholesome if you do it for unwholesome
reasons even if everybody else thinks
it's awesome
oh it's awesome to sit in a damn hole
with 50 people in silence that's that's
noble and beautiful it isn't often it
isn't because often people end up doing
it because they're still afraid to be
alone so they need support for their
practice which is supposed to develop
them as an individual that's a
constriction in terms you develop as an
individual by needing others you